## **Yash Thakur**

Location: Guelph, ON Canada | M: +1 (647) 466 2114 | E-mail: thakuryash@live.com

### **ABOUT ME**

With over seven years of experience in software development, have honed my skills in both front-end and back-end work. The primary focus has been on developing web applications that are user-friendly, visually attractive, and perform optimally on all devices. Make it a priority to keep updated with the latest industry trends and technologies to continually enhance the skillset. Deeply passionate about acquiring and applying new concepts into work while continuing to excel as a full-stack developer.

# **SKILLS AND QUALIFICATIONS**

- Proficient in JavaScript, TypeScript, ES5/ ES6, ReactJS, Jquery, CSS3, JSX &HTML5
- Back –end PHP, Node.js, Java, C#, .Net
- Excellent analytical and problem solving skills
- Object Oriented Programming
- Utilizing design patterns & data structures
- Agile software development
- Linux, Unix

- CSS Animations, LESS/Sass
- W3C Standards and AODA Compliancy
- Restful APIs, Express, GraphQL
- Git. Bitbucket
- Docker, Azure, AWS
- RDBMS,NoSQL

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Greentronic Ltd.**

Elmira, ON, Canada January 2024 - Present

#### Full Stack Developer

- Collaborated with the engineering team to design and implement a data tracing system for harvested products
- Engineered native cloud applications within Microsoft Azure, optimizing performance and scalability for Greentronics' solutions.
- Established and maintained robust communications with Greentronics field devices via modern APIs, facilitating seamless data exchange and system interoperability.
- Developed C#/.NET/ASP.NET solutions to process raw device data into SQL database records, enhancing data management and analysis capabilities.
- Designed intuitive frontend web interfaces using React and associated libraries (Vite, TanStack Query, MUI), catering to customer needs and enhancing user experiences.
- Conducted rigorous software testing to ensure application quality and reliability across diverse environments.
- Engaged in continuous collaboration and iteration to refine design and address challenges.

#### Cox Automotive - Dealer.com

Toronto, ON, Canada March 2020 - May 2023

### Web Developer II

- Provided technical oversight for a portfolio of 300+ clients on North America's leading online automotive sales platform.
- Provided technical support and training to a web development team, collaborating closely with a
  group of 15 sales representatives to effectively cater to the escalating need for customizing
  dealership website templates.
- Leveraged proficiency in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ReactJS, Typescript and Velocity to create
  customized websites for major dealership groups and original equipment manufacturers (OEMs),
  ensuring seamless functionality and design integration.
- Performed troubleshooting for issues pertaining to CSS, layouts, graphics, MUI and cross-browser

- compatibility to guarantee responsive design and optimal user experience.
- Integrated W3C standards and AODA compliance into website development practices.
- Maintained a heightened level of quality control to ensure peak performance and an exceptional user experience.
- Reviewed business and technical requirements, as well as designs, to ensure comprehensive understanding and alignment.

### Trader Corporation – autoTrader.ca

### Front-end Developer (Marketing Team)

Etobicoke, ON, Canada Sep 2019 - March 2020

- Developed a Web API utilizing Entity Framework to perform scraping and parsing of client information
- Developed and designed internal web applications to automate and streamline a vast number of manual processes relating to search engine APIs and social media advertising platforms
- Collaborate with designers, digital strategists, and team members to ensure branding and messaging requirements are met.
- Develop user-friendly forms, modify marketing assets, and implement tracking mechanisms for website metrics and campaign effectiveness.

### Web Developer

Etobicoke, ON, Canada May 2018 - Sep 2019

- Collaborate with WordPress Development & Creative Service team for high-quality custom development on the WordPress platform, including front-end coding and integration of HTML5, CSS3, JS/jQuery, SASS/LESS, MySQL, REACT, and PHP.
- Coordinate with internal/external partners to properly scope out projects, estimate hours, and propose alternative solutions.
- Create technical scope-of-work (SOW) documents.
- Meet deadlines and manage expectations around project timelines.
- Assist in discussions with technically advanced clients, addressing their questions and managing expectations.

### **Teknion**

### **Application Developer**

Etobicoke, ON, Canada Aug 2017 – May 2018

- Develop and maintain custom extensions for Teknion's StoryBoard implementation of Configura Software.
- Create 2D/3D product offerings with built-in costing, logic, and error prevention.
- Collaborate with Business Team(s) to develop StoryBoard Data Objects and resolve defects.
- Build and maintain Business Applications using open connectivity and established frameworks.
- Continuously improve code, processes, and technologies for enhanced efficiency and quality.

### **EDUCATION**

#### • Computer Programming - 2017

Humber Institute of Technology and Advanced Learning (Toronto, ON)

### Udemy courses

- The Modern GraphQL Bootcamp (with Node.js and Apollo) Andrew Mead
- Node.js, Express & MongoDB Dev to Deployment Brad Traversy
- React Front To Back Brad Traversy
- Azure(AZ-900) Scott Duffy

**Portfolio:** https://thakuryash.github.io/